So for most data visualization tasks,
对于大多数数据可视化任务,
we're just going to need two-dimensional computer graphics to plot and display the data.
我们只是需要二维计算机图形学来绘制和显示数据。
In order to do that, we'll need to use different coordinate systems.
为了做到这一点, 我们需要使用不同的坐标系。
We use a different coordinate system to plot the data than we use to display the data.
我们使用不同的坐标系来绘制数据, 而不是用来显示数据。
We're going to use two-dimensional graphics a lot when we visualize data.
当我们可视化数据时, 我们将使用二维图形。
We're used to using two-dimensional graphics, for example,
我们习惯于使用二维图形, 例如,
for plotting functions and so we'll focus on
绘制函数, 所以我们将重点放在
two-dimensional graphics now as we look at methods for using graphics for visualization.
二维图形现在, 我们看的方法, 使用图形可视化。
What we're going to learn is the difference between vector graphics,
我们会学到 矢量图形和光栅图形的区别
which are used to specify two-dimensional graphics and raster graphics,
用于指定二维图形和光栅图形,
which are used to display two-dimensional graphics.
用于显示二维图形。
And then we'll look at the coordinate system specifically that are used for each of them.
然后我们将详细地查看坐标系中每个它们所使用的坐标系统。
Vector graphics are the graphics that are used for drawing.
矢量图形是用于绘制的图形。
We're used to drawing; we take a pen and we'll put our pen down at
我们已经习惯画画了。我们拿一支钢笔, 把笔放在
one point and then we'll move our pen across
一点, 然后我们将我们的钢笔移动跨越
the paper and then lift our pen up at another point and you get
纸张, 然后举起我们的钢笔在另一个点, 你得到
a nice straight line between them - a nice continuous line.
一条很好的直线-一条很好的连续线。
In raster graphics, this is the graphics that are used,
在光栅图形中, 这是使用的图形,
for example, for our televisions and our phones;
例如, 我们的电视机和手机;
they are a rectilinear array of pixels and these pixels are assigned colors.
它们是像素的直线数组, 这些像素是指定的颜色。
And by assigning certain pixels certain colors,
通过指定某些像素的某些颜色,
you can represent those same shapes.
您可以代表相同的形状。
So you will draw a shape using vector graphics;
因此, 您将绘制一个形状使用矢量图形;
you will describe a point where you want to
你将描述一个点, 你想
start a line and a point where you want to stop
启动要停止的行和点
a line and you'll - you'll get
一条线, 你会-你会得到
either a straight line or a smooth curved line between them.
一条直线或它们之间的平滑曲线。
And those will be converted to raster graphics for display,
这些将被转换为光栅图形显示,
which will consist of the pixels that get illuminated along
这将包括的像素, 得到照亮沿
that path in order to display that path that you described with vector graphics.
该路径以显示您用矢量图形描述的路径。
So this process is called rasterization.
所以这个过程叫做栅格化。
And so we'll specify a primitive - as
因此, 我们将指定一个原始的
in a vector graphics format - we'll describe vertices,
以矢量图形格式-我们将描述顶点,
points on the plane.
点在飞机上。
And then we will connect those points with strokes - in this case, with straight lines,
然后我们将用笔画连接这些点-在这种情况下, 用直线,
but they could be curved paths - and then those strokes can - can enclose a region.
但它们可能是弯曲的路径, 然后这些笔画可以包围一个区域。
And so we can fill that region - and we may assign a color for that region.
因此, 我们可以填充该区域-我们可以为该区域指定颜色。
And for strokes who may assign a color and a width of
对于可能分配颜色和宽度的笔画,
the stroke or have the stroke stylized,
中风或中风的程式化,
say with dashed lines or so on.
用虚线等表示。
The process of rasterization starts with these primitives defined by
栅格化的过程从这些基元定义的
these few data points and converts
这些数据点和转换
them into an array of pixels so that they can be displayed.
它们放入一个像素数组中, 以便可以显示它们。
And so this raster format representation of this triangle is as an array of pixels.
所以这个三角形的光栅格式表示是作为一个像素数组。
And the dashed lines represent the original primitive on the left,
虚线表示左边的原始原语,
superimposed over the array of pixels that are - that are representing it.
叠加在表示它的像素数组中。
And in this case, we have pixels along the edges that are
在这种情况下, 我们有像素沿边缘
colored blue and pixels in the filled-in region that are colored pink.
颜色为粉红色的填充区域中的彩色蓝色和像素。
And you notice when we rasterize a shape,
你注意到当我们栅格化一个形状时,
we can get aliasing.
我们可以得到混淆。
And that's the fact that this nice straight line
这是事实, 这条漂亮的直线
here in our - in our vector graphics representation,
在我们的矢量图形表示中,
appears as a staircased line.
显示为 staircased 行。
You get the stairstep artifacts when you rasterize a smooth, straight line.
当你栅格化一条平滑的直线时, 你会得到一级分别的工件。
And because those stairsteps try to look like the original line,
因为那些 stairsteps 试着看起来像原来的线,
but look a little bit different,
但看起来有点不同,
we call that an alias;
我们称之为别名;
and that problem is called aliasing.
这个问题被称为别名。
When we draw primitives in two dimensions - when we want
当我们在两个维度中绘制基元时-当我们想要
to draw shapes for two-dimensional graphics - for example,
若要绘制二维图形的形状, 例如,
for plotting functions - we're going to need a coordinate system
对于绘制函数, 我们需要一个坐标系统
in which to draw those shapes so we know where to place the vertices,
在其中绘制这些形状, 以便我们知道放置顶点的位置,
for example, of a triangle.
例如, 三角形。
And so we need to define a coordinate system.
所以我们需要定义一个坐标系。
And these coordinates I will call canvas coordinates;
这些坐标, 我将调用画布坐标;
they're the coordinates that we're going to draw things with.
它们是我们要绘制的坐标。
In this case, the canvas coordinates have been defined to go from minus 1, minus 1
在这种情况下, 画布坐标被定义为从负1开始, 减去1
to 1, 1 and so they set up this square region of - of a plane.
到 1, 1, 所以他们建立了这一平面的平方区域。
The origin would be here in the middle.
起源将在这里在中间。
You can define your canvas coordinates to be anything you like.
你可以任意定义 你的画布坐标系
You want to define them to be something convenient so that you can
您希望将它们定义为方便的东西, 以便您可以
draw your shapes without a lot of trouble.
画你的形状，没有很多麻烦。
In this case, I've drawn a plot of a parabola - the parabola y equals x squared.
在这种情况下, 我画了一个抛物线的情节-抛物线 y 等于 x 的平方。
And so I've got a curved path starting at this point here going to this point here
所以我有一个弯曲的路径开始在这里这里要到这里的这一点
and I've defined my canvas coordinate system to be something convenient for that plot.
我已经定义了我的画布坐标系统是一个方便的情节。
In this case, I've started it going from minus one-eighth,
在这种情况下, 我已经开始从负 1/8,
minus one-eighth to one-and-one eighth, one-and-one-eighth.
减去1/8 到 1/8, 一和1/8。
And that's so that as I move one-eighth,
所以, 当我移动 1/8,
one-eighth in, I'm at the point 0, 0
1/8 在, 我在点 0, 0
in my coordinate system and I can draw my plot going from 0, 0 to 1, 1 here.
在我的坐标系中, 我可以画出我的剧情从 0, 0 到 1, 1 在这里。
And then I've got an additional eighth of a unit
然后我有一个额外的第八单位
surrounding the plot in order to do things - to add meta data,
围绕图, 添加元数据,
like the title of the visualisation and draw the axes and label the axes.
就像可视化的标题, 绘制坐标轴并标记坐标轴。
So that's convenient, but as I'm resizing the display,
所以这很方便, 但当我调整显示器的大小时,
I may want the fonts to be larger or
我可能希望字体更大或
smaller and I'll need a bigger margin surrounding the plot.
小, 我需要一个更大的边缘周围的情节。
Or I may want the plot to be larger and the margin to be smaller.
或者, 我可能希望该情节更大, 边缘更小。
So in - in two-dimensional computer graphics,
所以在二维计算机图形学中,
we can set up hierarchical coordinate systems.
我们可以建立层次坐标系。
And this just means you have a canvas in a canvas.
这就意味着画布上有画布。
In this case, we have a yellow canvas that is the coordinate system for
在这种情况下, 我们有一个黄色的画布, 是坐标系统的
the entire plot - the entire
整个情节-整个
visualization - and then we have
可视化-然后我们有
an inner canvas that is a coordinate system just for the plotted data;
内画布, 是用于绘制数据的坐标系统;
in this case, the parabola.
在这种情况下, 抛物线。
And so I've set up the outer coordinate system to go from 0, 0 to 1,
所以我建立了外部坐标系, 从 0, 0 到 1,
1 in this region and then I've set up an inner coordinate system to go
1在这个区域, 然后我已经建立了一个内部坐标系去
from one-tenth to nine-tenths and one-tenth,
从1/10 到9/10 和 1/10,
one-tenth to nine-tenths, nine-tenths
1/10 到 9/10, 9/10
here and I've defined its coordinate system to go from 0, 0 to 1, 1.
在这里, 我已经定义了它的坐标系从 0, 0 到 1, 1。
So now I can plot inside
所以现在我可以在里面画图
this coordinate system using coordinates that are convenient for plotting
这个坐标系使用的坐标, 方便绘图
this parabola and then I can plot in
这个抛物线, 然后我可以画图在
this outer coordinate system using coordinates convenient for drawing the decorations,
这个外坐标系使用坐标方便绘制装饰品,
the axes and the title.
坐标轴和标题。
And so we can define whatever coordinate system we want,
所以我们可以定义任何我们想要的坐标系,
wherever we want, in order to make it more convenient to draw two-dimensional graphics.
无论我们想要什么, 为了使它更方便地绘制二维图形。
There's also screen coordinates.
还有屏幕坐标。
And these are the coordinates that are used for raster graphics,
这些是用于光栅图形的坐标,
for the display of the information.
用于显示信息。
And in this coordinate system,
在这个坐标系中,
we have a grid going from 0, 0 to whatever our screen resolution is.
我们有一个网格从 0, 0, 无论我们的屏幕分辨率。
In this case, since we're going from 0, 0,
在这种情况下, 因为我们要从 0, 0,
we go to our horizontal resolution minus 1, vertical resolution minus 1.
我们去我们的水平分辨率减去 1, 垂直分辨率减去1。
If our screen resolution was 100, 100,
如果我们的屏幕分辨率是 100, 100,
we would be going from 0, 0 to 99, 99.
我们要从 0, 0 到 99, 99。
And the pixels are located on these grid intersections.
像素位于这些网格相交处。
And so you have a - a integer coordinate for each pixel location,
因此, 每个像素位置都有一个整数坐标,
which is useful when you're actually displaying an image using these pixels;
当您实际使用这些像素显示图像时, 该方法非常有用。
you want to be able to locate each one of these pixels.
您希望能够找到这些像素中的每一个。
And so there is a canvas-to-screen transformation that happens.
因此, 出现了一个画布到屏幕的转换。
So we're going to define our coordinate system going from some left
所以我们要定义我们的坐标系统从一些左
bottom point to some right top point
底部指向一些右上角
and and - and then we're going to plot using those coordinates.
然后-然后我们将使用这些坐标进行绘制。
And those coordinates are going to be converted to
这些坐标将被转换为
the corresponding pixel locations on our display screen.
显示屏幕上相应的像素位置。
And those pixel locations are going to be defined
这些像素位置将被定义
someplace on the display screen starting at x,
显示屏幕上的某个地方从 x 开始,
y and going to the point x plus the width
y 和去点 x 加上宽度
in pixels minus 1 and then y plus the height in pixels minus 1.
以像素减去 1, 然后 y 加上高度 (以像素为单位) 减去1。
So this coordinate system happens automatically and you can define these coordinates to
所以这个坐标系会自动发生, 你可以定义这些坐标来
be anything and you can define these coordinates to be any location on the screen.
任何东西, 你可以定义这些坐标是任何位置在屏幕上。
And so your 2D graphics that you're plotting on
所以你的2D 图形, 你正在画图
your canvas can be automatically resized and
您的画布可以自动调整大小, 并
repositioned anywhere on the screen just by
重新定位在屏幕上的任何地方只是通过
controlling this canvas-to-screen transformation.
控制此画布到屏幕的转换。
You can also work directly in screen coordinates by setting up
您还可以通过设置在屏幕坐标中直接工作
a canvas-to-screen transformation that uses
一个画布到屏幕的转换, 它使用
canvas coordinates that match up with your screen coordinates.
与屏幕坐标匹配的画布坐标。
In this case, you're just setting your left edge and your bottom edge to x and y
在这种情况下, 你只是设置你的左边缘和你的底部边缘到 x 和 y
and you're right edge and your top edge to x and y
你是正确的边缘和你的上边缘 x 和 y
plus the width minus 1 and the height minus 1.
加上宽度减去1和高度减去1。
And in this case, you can specify the coordinates of your primitives in
在这种情况下, 您可以指定基元的坐标在
vector graphics using the same coordinates
使用相同坐标的矢量图形
for the pixels that - that they will be translated to.
对于它们将被翻译成的像素。
I don't recommend doing this because when you're working in screen coordinates,
我不建议这样做, 因为当你在屏幕坐标工作,
you're not going to know what your output screen display device might be.
您将不知道输出屏幕显示设备可能是什么。
It could be a cell phone,
可能是手机
it could be a television, it could be a watch,
它可能是一台电视, 它可能是一只手表,
it could be a video wall - and all of those will have different resolutions
这可能是一个视频墙-所有这些将有不同的解决方案
and you want to make sure that your two-dimensional graphics is properly displayed;
你要确保你的二维图形正确显示;
it's not too small or too large when it's displayed on different devices.
它不太小或太大, 当它显示在不同的设备上。
So it's better to work in some canvas coordinates that's convenient for you and let
因此, 最好的工作在一些帆布坐标, 这是方便你, 让
the canvas-to-screen transformation worry
画布到屏幕的转换担心
about converting it to the corresponding pixels.
关于将其转换为相应的像素。
So what have we learned?
这节课我们都学了什么
We've learned that vector graphics is used to describe shapes and that
我们学了矢量图形 用于描述形状
raster graphics are what we use to display those shapes using a table of pixels.
而光栅图用像素表来 显示这些形状
And that we can set up coordinates that - that are convenient for us to plot in a canvas
我们可以设置坐标, 这是方便我们在画布上绘制
and those coordinates are different from
这些坐标不同于
the raster coordinates that we use to display the canvas.
用于显示画布的光栅坐标。
And we can set up canvases within a canvas,
我们还能在画布中嵌套画布
which allows us to divide up the screen in ways that make it more convenient
这使得我们可以用更方便的方式分割屏幕
for us to set up a two-dimensional visualization display.
为我们建立一个二维可视化显示。
So we learned that we describe shapes using vector graphics,
所以我们学会了用矢量图形描述形状,
but we display shapes using raster graphics.
但我们使用光栅图形显示形状。
We can describe our shapes using the coordinate system of raster graphics,
我们可以使用光栅图形的坐标系来描述我们的形状,
the coordinate systems of the screens pixels,
屏幕像素的坐标系统,
or we can describe them using the canvas coordinates of our vector graphics,
或者, 我们可以用我们的矢量图形的画布坐标来描述它们,
or we - we can use whatever coordinate system is most convenient for us to plot the data.
或者我们-我们可以使用任何坐标系统是最方便的, 我们绘制数据。